Wow.
>> Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded for the
whole world to keep. Brother Tanzel,
>> and God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which hath brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any grave in image or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. Why the Lord thy God am
a jealous God, visiting the iniquities
of the fathers upon the children, unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me, and showing thousand
showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt take the name of the Lord thy
God in vain. For the Lord will not hold
him, guilt that take up his name in
vain. Remember the Sabbath day to keep
it holy. Six days shall thy lab do all
thy work, but the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In it thou
shalt not do any work. Thou nor thy son,
nor thy daughter, thy man's servant, nor
thy maid servant, nor thy cattle, and
nor thy stranger that is within thy
gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hallowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shall not kill.
Thou sh not commit adultery. Thou shall
not steal. Thou not bear false wings
against thy neighbor. Thou not cover thy
neighbor's house. Thou has not covered
thy neighbor's wife, nor his man's
servant, nor his maid servant, nor his
ox, nor his ass, nor anything that is
thy neighbors. We read Exodus 21-17.
May the Lord have a blessing to the
reading of his words. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
All right. Here on question and answer,
you can ask us a question and we'll
answer according to the King James
Bible. And if we cannot find the answer,
we will seek further counsel to bring
you an answer at a later time. The
questions we will not answer are the
vague long scripture questions as well
as questions of debate. We are not here
to debate. We are here to spread the
true gospel of Jesus. So please be as
direct as possible with your questions
so we can be as direct as possible with
our answers out of the King James Bible.
No other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also keep
in mind this is a live stream. So feel
free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you please keep them to a
two scripture maximum. But let me
introduce to you the family that's on
the panel this evening. Brother Dre,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Jerome,
>> grace and peace.
>> Brother Julius,
>> good evening everybody.
>> Brother Tanzel,
>> good evening.
>> Sister Deborah,
Brother Sean or
>> good evening
>> and we have the guest caller with us and
I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question of the
evening?
>> Uh yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. So
Marcus Kimbro says, "My friend's wife
separated from him and has been
separated for two years. They were still
dealing with each other and he is still
supporting her. They had a big argument
and now she wants a divorce and says she
is going to find another husband that
has more in common with her.
Is it lawful for her to divorce her
husband and go and find another husband
to marry?
>> All right, we got us a marital question
here and we're going to ask the guest
caller.
>> Answer is no.
All right,
we're going to leave it right there and
we're going to move on to our next
question.
>> Next one. Via live via Celite asks, "Who
is the tax collector in Daniel 11 verse
20?"
>> Daniel 11
and verse 20. They're asking who is this
tax collector in that scripture?
Um, and the guest caller take it from
there. Daniel 11 and verse 20.
>> Read it.
>> Then shall stand up in his estate a
raise of taxes in the glory of the
kingdom. But within few days he shall be
destroyed neither in anger nor in
battle.
Answer that is I don't know.
>> All right.
So we're going to leave it right there
and we're going to move on to our next
question.
>> The next one is from Patrice Morgan.
Um, she asks, "What is the Bible stance
on tattoos?
Are they considered
in the same regards as piercings?"
>> All right. In the Bible, when we talking
about tattoos as well as piercings,
Brother Julius,
repeat that question.
The question was, "What is the Bible
stance on tattoos? Are they considered
in the same regard as piercings?
>> Tattoos only for the dead." What's that
scripture, Drake? Only for the dead.
>> Leviticus 19.
>> Yeah. Because the book told you that uh
there was instances where people would
have piercings. Israel always had
piercings, you know, nose jewelry,
stomach jewelry, whatever.
Tattoos. Leviticus 19. Let's go there.
Leviticus
28. A bag up.
[clears throat]
Mm-
>> Let's pick this up at verse 27.
>> Go ahead, T.
>> You shall not round the corners of your
head, neither shall thou mar the corners
of thy beard.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And you shall not make any cutings in
your flesh for the dead.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Nor print any marks upon you. I am the
Lord. Now, they use needles uh to to
insert tattoos, which is to uh put the
ink in there. Put that's a if if if it's
for the dead, you don't do it. If it's
for the dead,
you know, and you don't make no cutings
for the dead. That's all the books say
about that. That's the best I can do.
Anybody else? Anybody else?
>> All right.
>> So, Deuteronomy 14 and1 is another
scripture that says the same thing.
>> Deuteronomy.
>> Let's go there.
>> Yeah. Deuteronomy 14 and1.
>> When you get it to Deuteronomy 14:1,
>> you are the children of the Lord your
God. Ye shall not cut yourself nor make
any baldness between your eyes for the
dead.
>> That's that's all we got.
>> That's all we got, Cornell.
[clears throat]
>> All right. So, we're going to leave it
right there and we're going to move on
to our next question.
>> Next question. Why don't IG Bible study
classes read or teach the book of Enoch?
Was was wasn't it also an original book
of the Bible?
>> All right. So, brother Julius, at the
beginning of the program, we say we
don't acknowledge any other books or
programs or books on this show rather,
but they asking about the book of Enoch.
Go right ahead, my brother.
>> First of all, we there's nothing wrong
with reading books. We read the books.
We read the Apocrypha. We don't teach
it.
Why? Because it is an apocryphal book.
It is a pseudo uh pseudographical book.
And pseudographical, the definition of
pseudographical
is um
is still from the Greek it means falsely
inscribed.
Falsely inscribed. And to a a famous
writer, but not the original author.
That's why you can't find out who wrote
the apocrypha some written somewhere
between uh the book of Enoch and all
those books in between there. It was
added the Apocrypha system and brothers
I would love to crush this once and for
all. The Apocrypha was added by the
Council of Trent in 1546.
That's the Catholic Church. They added
it and they placed it between the old
and new testament and they pronounced
anathema banned or cursed on anybody
that rejected it. So it's a forced thing
that was added. It was never a part of
the Bible. It was added by the Catholic
Church and then uh forced to be added in
1611 but then later on removed
by the Protestants. So therefore, the uh
book of e the book of Enoch, if you read
the book of Enoch and you read the
Bible, why come Jesus never mentioned
it? Why come the apostles never
supported it or mention it? Because it
is not holy. It is fake. It is added and
attributed to famous people like Enoch
or the book of Jubilees, but it's all
false. So the Israel of God, we don't
teach it. We only teach Genesis to
Revelation because everything from
Genesis to Revelation appertain to
salvation.
That's the best I can do with that. So
you mess with the book, you going to
confuse yourself. It is false. It is
fake. That's what the word apocrypha
mean. Fake. False. That's all I got.
>> Okay. What was that word? Pause there,
Debbie.
>> Okay. Repeat.
What was the other part of that
question? What? Yeah.
>> Repeat, Deborah.
>> Uh, all right. Uh, was it also an
original book of the Bible that's
talking about Enoch?
>> No, it was added by the Council of Trent
in 1546.
1546. Go and do your own research,
sisters and brothers. Look up the
Council of Trent. It was added by the
Catholic Church fathers
and forced uh under the threat of being
banned or cursed by the Catholic Church
if you did not support it.
>> Okay. What was that word you used at the
beginning? Pseudographical.
>> It is uh what they call a pseudo uh
pseudapigrapher.
Pseudapigrapher.
Look up that definition.
Pseudapigrapher. It will tell you
falsely inscribed and credited to make
it seem like it's by one of the authors
of the Bible and it's not.
>> What they call it today copyright
infringement.
>> Yeah.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered that question. And we
move on to our next one.
>> Next one. In Psalms 5 verse 11, what
does love by name mean?
All right, let's go there uh Tenzel
and let's read that Psalms five and read
verse 11 and 12 for me. Psalms 5 11 and
12. Go ahead. But let all those that put
their trust in thee rejoice, and let
them ever shout for joy, because thou
defend them, and let them also that love
thy name be joyful in thee. Yeah.
>> For our Lord will bless the righteous
with favor with thou compass him as for
the shield.
So we see belove let all those that put
their trust in thee rejoice and let them
ever shout for joy because once you know
the name and we're going to use the name
Jesus here and once you know and you
follow him and you keep his commandments
and do what he say hey he's going to
bless you with righteousness according
to his word and we are supposed to shout
for joy because we have found him. But
let's read a little bit more about that
name Jesus. Let's go to Philippians 2,
brother. Philippians
the 2 chapter.
Philippians the 2 chapter. Cuz this name
here is above every name, right?
Philippians 2 and read that verse five.
And then we're going to skip down to
verse 8. Read that verse five because it
is the name that we also love. And we
want to have the same mind as the one
who came and died for the sins of the
world. Go ahead.
>> Let this mind be in you which was also
in Christ Jesus.
>> So now we got us a name. Skip down to
verse eight and go ahead.
>> And being found in fashion as a man, he
humbled himself and became obedient unto
death, even the death of the cross.
>> So we talking about this same Jesus who
came to die for the sins of the world.
Verse N. Wherefore God also have highly
exalted him and given him a name which
is above every name.
>> Yes.
>> That at the name of Jesus every knee
should bow of things in heaven and
things in earth and things under the
earth.
>> Yes.
>> That every tongue should confess that
Jesus Christ is Lord to the glory of God
the Father.
>> Yes. Because we love that name, Tanzel,
because he came and saved us and gave us
an opportunity to have salvation, didn't
he?
>> That's right.
>> Now, let's go over to that Acts 4. Go to
Acts the 4th chapter.
>> Because a lot of times this name is is
disrespected in a way where we attribute
to people that don't have knowledge
because this is your only way out of
that room. The only way out of the room.
Acts four. And let's read pick it up at
that verse 10.
Acts 4 and10.
Go ahead, brother. Be it known unto you
all and to all the people of Israel,
that by the name of Jesus Christ of
Nazareth, whom he crucified, whom God
raised from the dead, even by him doeth
this man stand here before you.
>> Go ahead. This is the stone which was
set at not of you builders, which is
become the head of the corner.
>> And they made very light of that stone
that came to die for everybody. But he
has become the head of the corner, even
making light of him today. Verse 12. And
then we're going to go to Matthew's one
after that. Verse 12. Go ahead. Neither
is there salvation any other. For there
is none other name under heaven given
among men whereby we must be saved.
>> And we must love that name if we want to
be saved.
Matthew the first chapter. Go to Matthew
1. And that'll be it. Matthew 1.
And let's pick it up, brother. We're
going we're going to read that verse 18
and then we're going to skip down to
verse 21. Read that verse 18 because
this was told to Mary before Jesus even
came in the flesh cuz he came to die for
the sins. Go ahead. Matthew 1:18.
Now the birth of Jesus Christ was on
this wise whereas his mother Mary was
expoused to Joseph before they came
together she was found with child of the
Holy Ghost.
>> Yes. Because this name was sent from
heaven and we got a name again Jesus
Christ. Skip down to 21. Go ahead.
>> And she shall bring forth a son, and
thou shalt call his name Jesus.
>> Yes. That's why we love that name. Go
ahead.
>> That's right. But he shall save his
people from their sins.
>> Oh. Save his people from their sins and
everybody else who believe and love that
name and obey him cuz all have sinned
and come short of the glory of God. Read
24 and 25. That'll be it. Then Joseph
been raised from sleep did as the angel
of the Lord had bidden him and took unto
him his wife
>> Mary who had Jesus. Right. Go ahead.
>> Right.
>> 25
>> and knew her not till she had brought
forth her firstborn son. And he called
his name Jesus.
>> Jesus. That's why we love that name,
>> right?
>> Because we know all that he has done for
us. And he came and died for the sins.
That's all I got. Anybody else?
Okay, we're getting a little feedback on
one of the lines there.
If we could correct that, that would be
great.
Okay. So, we hope that that answered
your question and we love that name
based on all he has done for all who
believe in him and serve him out of a
pure heart.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Okay,
we're going to move on to our next
question, Sister Deborah with a time
check.
>> Yes, the time is 7:49.
Uh, circumcision.
Nowadays, circumcision is not automatic
when you are born in the hospital. So,
being at the age of 67 years old, would
the Lord give you a pass if you are not
circumcised?
>> All right. Will the Lord give you a pass
if you are not circumcised? Yes. Caller.
Let's start.
First, we're going to start with the
stranger.
All right.
>> All right.
>> And this is going to take place when the
Lord is back on the earth. [snorts]
We're going to go to Ezekiel
44th chapter.
We're going to start reading at verse
six because the apostles got together
and let the stranger that the uh uh
and they decided at at Paul's in at
Paul's cushioning not to circumcise a
stranger. They even wrote a letter
saying such you know but we're going to
show you what the Lord think about this.
This is even when he is back on the
earth. Let's go to Ezekiel 44. And we're
going to read verses 6 and 7 first.
Read it when you get there.
>> And thou shalt say to the rebellious,
even to the house of Israel, thus sayeth
the Lord God, oh ye house of Israel, let
it suffice you of all your abominations,
and that ye have brought into my
sanctuary strangers uncircumcised in
heart and uncircumcised in flesh to be
in my sanctuary.
blessing. He said that's an abomination.
Said the vice is abomination that you
done brought into my my sanctuary
strangers.
>> I'm circumcised in the heart and in the
flesh. Go ahead.
>> To pollute it even my house when you
offer my bread, the fat and the blood
and they have broken my covenant because
of all your abomination.
So now he's saying this to Israel
because of your abomination and it took
place when they argued about whether the
strangers should be circumcised or not.
It was never about Israel.
>> Right
>> now
because of your abomination, you have
caused them to break my covenant. Now
look what he now but can the apostles
decide whe the stranger should get a
satisfied circumcised and the Lord to go
along with it.
Reason I'm putting it like this because
the question is asked you know because
of uh it's not common. Do you think the
Lord will go along with it? Well look
what the Lord said concerning that. Skip
down and read verse N.
Mhm.
>> Thus said the Lord God, "No stranger
uncircumcised in heart, nor
uncircumcised in flesh, shall enter into
my sanctuary of any stranger that is
among the children of Israel."
>> So now,
if a stranger can't enter in, can
anybody else? No. If you're
uncircumcised in the heart, didn't it
say? And the flesh. That's talking about
the mind and the body. Ain't that
correct?
>> That's right. Right.
Now, let's go back and look at when the
commandment was given, the the covenant
was made concerning the circumcision.
Let's go back into the Genesis 17th
chapter
and read from verses 10 to 14.
Genesis 17 verses 10.
This is my covenant which ye shall keep
between me and you and thy seed after
thee. Every man child among you shall be
circumcised. And you shall circumcise
the flesh of your foreskin. And there
shall be a token of the covenant betw
twix me and you. And he that is 8 days
old shall be circumcised among you,
every manch child in your generation. He
that is born in the house or bought with
money of any stranger which is not of
thy seed. And he that is born in thy
house and he that is bought with thy
money must needs be circumcised.
And my covenant shall be in your flesh
for an everlasting covenant. Are they
uncircumcised?
>> Look at this strong word he used. Must
needs be circumcised. [clears throat]
And this the Lord talking to Abraham.
Abraham didn't ask him. He volunteered
and gave this information. Must need be
circumcised. But keep reading.
>> And the uncircumcised man child whose
flesh of his foreskin is not
circumcised. That soul shall be cut off
from his people. He have broken my
covenant.
>> Now the Lord said that,
>> right?
>> Can you reverse the Lord? He said, "You
must need circumcised." And any any
manchild, whether he's born in the house
or bought with money, which represent
being purchased with the blood of Jesus,
if he's uncircumcised, [clears throat]
he going to be cut off from among his
brethren. Did I need to interpret that?
>> Mhm.
>> So now, brother say 74 years old.
>> 67.
>> 67 years old. Does that exempt him?
Let's see.
>> Skip down and read
verse 24.
>> And Abraham was 90 years old and nine
when he was circumcised in the flesh of
his foreskin.
>> That's a little older than the gentleman
that asked the question. So the answer
is no. God ain't going to give you no
break. When you know better, you do
better.
>> That's right. And for you to answer that
question, that mean you know better. I
advise you to get circumcised.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right. We hope that that answered
your question there as we continue to
move on to our next question.
>> Next one. Will flesh and blood still
have to work during Jesus Christ
1,000year reign?
or flesh and blood still have to roll up
their sleeves and work during Christ's
thousand-y year reign. Brother Jerome,
well, [clears throat] if they still want
to feed themselves and if they got a
family feed their family, they need to
work even during the Lord's um thousand
year um reign. cuz as you know according
to your question you know it's going to
be flesh and blood uh in the son's
kingdom you know so yeah they they need
to still work uh it's a verse in um
Thessalonians
uh 2 Thessalonians the 3r chapter verse
10 if you can go there Tanzel
>> 2 Thessalonians verse 10
>> yeah yeah Second Thessalonians the 3
verse 10.
>> Okay.
>> Read that.
>> But even when we were with you, this we
commanded you that if any would not
work, neither should he eat.
>> Yeah. So if you don't want to work, he
said, "Well, maybe you shouldn't eat
then if you don't want to work." Uh but
uh you can read in Isaiah the 65th
chapter when the Lord's kingdom is here,
you can read where people are still
going to be laboring, you know, doing
work, you know. So, um that's all I got
on if anybody want to add something.
>> All right.
Um,
okay. We're going to leave it right
there. So, the answer is yes. You You'll
still be working.
>> All right. We're going to move on to our
next question, Sister Deborah.
>> Yes. Next one. Is it wrong to swear at
court?
>> Is it wrong to swear at court? You know
how you have to raise your hand and
swear in court? Brother Dre, what you
say?
Let's go to Matthew the 5th chapter.
[clears throat] Matthew 5
and we going to pick it up at verse 33.
Go ahead, brother Tanzel.
>> Again, ye have heard that it hath been
said by them of old time, thou shall not
forear thyself,
but shall perform unto the Lord thine
oath. Mhm.
>> But I say unto you, swear not at all,
neither by heaven, for it is God's
throne.
>> Now skip down to and read verse 37.
>> But let your communication be yay or nay
nay. But whatsoever is more than the
these cometh of evil.
>> That's right. Now, let's go over the
numbers. We just going to read one verse
there. Numbers 30
and verse two. Numbers 30 and two.
>> Right.
>> When you get there, go ahead, brother.
>> If a man bow a vow unto the Lord or
swear an oath to bind his soul with a
bond, he shall not break his word, he
shall do according to all that is
proceeded out of his mouth.
>> That's right. So you can affirm. You
don't have to swear. You can affirm to
tell the truth, but if you swear,
then make sure that you do all that. You
you don't break the word that you
swearing to. That's all I got.
>> Yeah. Right, brother Dre.
>> I used to go to court. When I go to
court, I would the judge would say,
"Hold your right hand up. Do you swear
to tell the truth, the whole truth, and
nothing but the truth?" And I would say,
"I affirm."
>> Yes. That means the maintain is true.
>> Yeah. Yeah. They they've even gotten a
little more wiser to that because uh
they'll ask you sometimes in some
courts, do you swear or affirm?
>> Yes.
>> To tell the truth. So you could just say
at that point, I affirm while others who
may not have no knowledge say swear.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother
Dre and brother Julius. As we move on to
our next question,
>> next one. I am a New Testament believer.
And Paul stated in 2 Corinthians 12:E2
that he was caught up to heaven and also
that he had a crown laid up for him in 2
Timothy 4
7 and 8. What can you say to this?
>> All right. So 2 Corinthians 12 and 2 and
then that's 2 Timothy 4 7 and 8. What
light can you shine on that, brother
Julius?
>> Well, you said that you are a New
Testament believer
and you said that Paul said that he was
caught up to the to uh to heaven. Let's
go and see what Paul actually said.
Now, you have to uh you said that you're
a New Testament believer, but you're
putting words in Paul's mouth. 2
Corinthians 12
[clears throat]
and pick it up at verse two.
When you get it to uh Tail, go ahead and
read it.
>> I knew a man in Christ above 14 years
ago. Whether in the body I cannot tell,
or whether out of the body, I cannot
tell. God knoweth such a one caught up
to the third heaven. Now, Paul didn't
tell you that he was caught up in
heaven. He said he knew a man that was
caught up in heaven.
Let's go and let's see what the book say
about this. Let's see what the book say
about this. Let's see. Has a man been
caught up to heaven. Let's go to St.
John 3.
St. John 3. Tenzel.
St. John 3 and read verse 13 when you
get it. St. John 3 and 13.
>> And no man have ascended up to heaven,
>> but he that came down from heaven, even
the son of man which is in heaven.
>> Oh, so Paul was talking about Jesus.
>> Right?
>> Let me tell you why he was talking to
Jesus. Because
he told you he knew a man he was caught
up to the third heaven,
>> right?
>> Then he told then we read in John Jesus
himself told you that no man has
ascended up to heaven. So let's look at
let's look at this again. Now you say
you're a New Testament believer, but you
got to read the book and don't add to
it. Let's go to second Timothy the 4th
chapter.
Second Timothy chapter 4
and let's look at what Paul said to
Timothy.
[clears throat]
Pick it up at verse uh 5. 2 Timothy 4
and we're going to read verse 5 and then
we're going to skip to verse seven. Go
ahead T. But watch thou in all things,
endure affliction, and do the work of an
evangelist. Make full proof of thy
ministry.
>> This is what Paul instructs to Timothy
is. Skip down to verse seven and
continue.
>> I have fought a good fight.
>> Yes,
>> I have finished my course.
>> I have kept the faith.
>> Paul say he fought a good fight because
he's in this spiritual fight. And he
said he's kept the faith. Go ahead at
verse eight.
Henceforth there is laid up for me a
crown of righteousness
which the Lord the righteous judge shall
give me at that day.
>> At that day that is Christ. Well, we
going to let the book. It's going to
tell you at that day. Paul didn't tell
you I'm going to heaven and I'm going
get a crown right now. He told you I got
a crown laid up for me. Continue.
>> And not to me only, but unto all them
also that love his appearing. Now, so
Paul said, "I'mma get my crown and not
me only, but everybody who died in
Christ or who love Christ, whether
they're alive or whether they died in
Christ at that day." Let's go to First
Thessalonians 10il
chapter.
And this is why the scripture say you
have to rightly divide the word of
truth.
>> That's right.
>> And pick it up at verse 14.
1 Thessalonians 4 and4. They call this
the rapture chapter and that is a lie.
It is the second coming of the Lord. Go
ahead and read that 14.
>> For if we believe that Jesus died and
rose again, [clears throat]
>> even so them also which sleep in Jesus
will God bring with them.
>> And he going to meet him in the air. Go
ahead. For this we say unto you by the
word of the Lord, that we which are
alive and remain unto the coming of the
Lord,
>> Uhhuh.
>> shall not prevent them which are asleep.
>> Yes.
>> For the Lord himself shall descend from
heaven.
>> Wait a minute. Wait a minute. In order
to descend from heaven, he had to be
there.
>> Right.
>> Continue.
>> With a shout.
>> Uhhuh.
>> With the voice of the archangel.
>> Yes.
>> With the trump of God. And the dead in
Christ shall rise first.
>> Uhhuh.
>> The dead in Christ shall rise first. Go
ahead.
>> Then we which are alive and remain shall
be caught up together with them in the
clouds.
To meet the Lord in the air,
and so shall we ever be with the Lord.
>> Now, in order to find out where the Lord
going to be, which is on this earth, you
got to go to Zechariah the 14th chapter.
>> Right? Cuz the Lord when you read that
chapter, we can go there real quick.
Zechariah
14.
This is why he told you no man has
ascended into heaven because you didn't
come from heaven.
>> Christ came from heaven. He got a right
to say it back up.
Let's read fast with this one. T verse
one. Go ahead. We're talking about the
day of the Lord. At that day, Paul said,
"And I got a reward. At that day, I'm
going to get mine and everybody that
love is appearing at that day." Now,
here's that day. Verse one.
>> Behold, the day of the Lord cometh, and
thor shall be divided in the midst of
thee. I will gather all nations against
Jerusalem to battle, and the city shall
be taken, and the house is rife, and the
woman is ravished, and half of the city
shall go into captivity, and the residue
of the people shall not be cut off from
the city.
>> Then shall the Lord go forth and fight
against those nations, as when he fought
in the day of battle,
>> and his peace shall stand in that day
upon the Mount of Olives,
>> that's on this earth. Go ahead. which is
before Jerusalem on the east, and the
Mount of Olives shall cleave in the
midst thereof towards the east and
towards the west.
>> Yes.
>> And there shall be a very great valley,
and half of the mountain shall remove
toward the north, and half of it towards
the south.
>> Yes.
>> Ye shall flee to the valley of the
mountains, for the valley of the
mountain shall reach unto Ael. Yeah, you
shall flee like as he fled [snorts] from
before the earthquake in the days of
Uzziah, king of Judah. Uh-huh.
>> And the Lord my God shall come and all
the saints with thee.
>> So now Paul was a saint. So all the
saints that is the those who are
righteous and alive, they going to get
their glorified bodies. And the dead,
they going to come out that grave with
their glorified bodies including Paul,
>> right?
>> And everybody gonna get their crown at
that day and not one moment before. And
if you read first Timothy the uh uh
sixth chapter if he Paul told you that
Christ only have immortality. So
everybody including Paul that's ever
died right they are in the grave sisters
and brothers. So
continue to listen here to the Israel of
God. And we have the Israel of God has a
lesson called the dead. Where are they?
Heaven, hell or in the grave? So,
it's good that you're a New Testament
believer, but you got to go back to the
Old Testament.
>> Okay? The Old Testament told you, "Dust
thou art, and until dust shall thou
return until a resurrection." That's all
I got.
>> Let me throw in one thing.
>> First Corinthians 15th chapter, start
reading at verse 21,
23.
1 Corinthians 15 and verse 41.
>> For since by man came death, and by man
came also the resurrection of the dead.
For as in Adam all died, and even so in
Christ shall all be made alive. But
every man in his own order, Christ the
first fruits, and afterwards they that
are Christ at his coming.
That's what he said, man. Uhuh.
Everybody in his own order.
Christ the first fruit and those that
are Christ at his.
>> That's right.
>> As long as Jesus come, you're in the
grave. But what happened to you? the
person that asked the question, they
might believe in the Old Testament but
New Testament but they don't read it cuz
had they read it and would have said
when Paul said I knew a man over so many
years
whether in the body out
one caught up to the third heaven he's
talking about the man talking Jesus not
himself I can't see
>> ideas that you could read that and come
up with this Paul going to heaven
instead of Jesus. That's all I have to
say.
>> Thank you, G.
>> Thank you very much. Hope that that
answered your question as we continue to
move on to our next question.
>> Next one. In first Thessalonians 5 verse
15, what does rendering evil for evil
mean?
>> All right, let's go to that first
Thessalonian
five.
And let's pick it up at that verse
15, brother Tanzel, and go right ahead.
>> That none ren evil for evil unto any
man, but every but ever follow that
which is good, both among yourselves and
to all men.
>> All right. So see that none render evil
to evil unto any man, but never follow
that which is good. because the Lord is
the one that pays everybody back who
violates whether it's you or someone
else. But you know, they even came out
with a song, you know, the big payback
revenge. I don't know karate, but I know
and all that stuff even encouraging you
to seek your own revenge. But the book
don't back that up. But let's go into uh
Romans.
Let's go into that Romans the 12th
chapter, brother.
Because God, hey, he can reward and pay
back much better than all of us put
together.
Romans 12 and let's pick it up, brother,
at that verse 9. Romans 12 and 9. And
then we're going to skip down. Go ahead.
Let love be without dissimulation
and abhore that which is evil and cleave
to that which is good. So you see how
the Lord tell us that we are supposed to
hate evil. You can't hate it and then
turn around and do evil. But he say let
love be without this simulation. Don't
have this false appearance. You go love
love. And Lord say but hate the evil and
cleave to that which is good. But skip
down, brother, to that verse 17 and go
ahead.
>> Recompense to no man evil for evil.
Provide things honest in the sight of
all men.
>> So there we go. Recompense to no man
evil for evil. Go ahead.
>> If it be possible, as much as life and
you live peaceably with all men.
>> If it be possible, live peaceibly. And
sometimes living peaceibly is also
keeping your distance. Sometimes you
just got to stay your distance for peace
sake. Go ahead.
>> Dearly beloved, avenge not yourselves,
but rather give place unto wrath. For it
is written, vengeance is mine. I will
repay, sayeth the Lord.
>> Oh, so the Lord said, don't avenge
yourself. You know, give place unto
wrath. Cuz sometimes, hey, some
situations or people or whatever the
case might be really don't like you and
you have to, hey, stick to the Lord and
let him repay anybody that got it
coming. Verse 20.
Therefore, thy enemy hunger, feed him.
And if he thirst, give him drink. For in
so doing, thou shalt keep coals on fire
on his head. Oh, even your enemy if he's
thirsty, you have to give him drink and
you have to feed him if he is hungry.
Because if you was wearing them shoes,
you would hope that somebody would give
you something to drink or something to
eat during your time of need. Verse 21.
>> Be not overcome of evil, but overcome
evil with good.
>> That's right. So, don't be overcome with
evil, trying to pay people back and all
that stuff. You let God handle that and
you just keep on doing your good and
letting your light shine and hey, God
will do the rest.
That's all I got.
>> I want to give us
>> I want a simple
>> I want to make a simple
>> scenario.
>> Somebody shoot somebody shoot your cat.
That's evil.
And if you turn around and shoot they
cat because he shot your cat,
>> that's what you call rendering evil for
evil.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> All I got to say.
>> All right. So, we hope that that
answered your question, Sister Deborah.
Next question.
>> Uh, next question. Is Abraham the father
of Isaac and Ishmael? And if so, how did
Ishmael become the head of Islam, the
Arabs?
>> All right, asking about some lineage
here. It looks like gas caller.
>> Yeah, Abraham is a father of Ishmael,
but Ishmael didn't have nothing to do
with Islam. Those are his children.
Those are the one that come up with it.
And uh uh
because uh Abraham
uh uh uh because the Bible nowhere that
says Ishma was a Muslim.
So who was a Muslim? Who was the one
that headed the Muslim uh h movement?
His children. Go to [clears throat]
Genesis the 17th chapter and read verse
20.
Genesis 17
>> and verse 20.
And as for Ishmael, I have heard thee,
behold, I have blessed him, and will
make him fruitful, and will multiply him
exceedingly. 12 princes shall he
begotten, and I will make him a great
nation.
>> So, we had 12, son. which come up with
12 nations
uh you know 12 states that's why
sometime when they talk about the Arab
they say they always talk about the 13
Arab states that's because they have
taken over Egypt but Egypt don't belong
to the Arabs so Ishmael was not a Muslim
neither did he put it forth it was the
children out of him down through the
generation
that come up with that that's all I have
to say
>> all Right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> We hope that that answered your question
there as we keep on moving.
>> Uh, yes. What is Luke 23 verse 54
referring to?
>> What is Luke 23 and 54 talking about?
Brother Jerome,
let's go read it.
You get it? Go ahead and read.
>> In that day was the preparation of the
Sabbath drew on.
>> Okay. Um
uh that's that's actually referring to
uh the Passover.
Uh
Passover is the day that come before the
first day of the feast of unleaven
bread.
And the reason why they call they refer
to it as the preparation is because um
they're making preparations in order to
keep the feast of Passover that that's
going to follow. Okay. Uh so let's go
read um St. John
chapter 19 and verse 31.
St. John chapter 19 verse 31.
Go ahead.
>> The Jews therefore because it was the
preparation that the body should not
remain upon the cross on the Sabbath
day. For that Sabbath day was a high
day. beside Pilot that their legs might
be broken and that they might be taken
away.
>> Yeah. So in that verse, the preparation
day was actually the Passover when Jesus
was on the cross. Okay. Uh and the high
day in that same verse was the day that
followed which is the first day of the
feast of unleven bread. Okay? Passover
fall on the 14th day and um the first
day of the feast of unleven bread fall
on the 15th day of the first month. A
bill. So let's let's go read that and
that'll be it. Uh Leviticus the 23rd
chapter verse 4-6.
>> Leviticus 23.
>> Yes.
>> 4-6.
These are the feasts of the Lord, even
holy convocation, which he shall
proclaim in their season. In the 14th
day of the first month at evening is the
Lord Passover.
>> And on the 15th day of the same month is
the feast of unleaven bread unto the
Lord. Seven days ye must eat unleaven
bread.
>> Yeah,
that's all I got on.
I just want to make a quickction.
>> Yes, sir.
>> See, uh, Jesus ate the Passover on the
14th day.
>> Yeah.
>> The evening time when it was done. But
then he was killed in the daytime of the
Passover.
>> Yeah.
>> And they wanted him off the cross cuz
there was a day they had to prepare
to keep feast of unleven bread which is
on the 15th day.
>> Okay.
Don't have to say.
>> All right.
All right. We're gonna leave it right
there and we going to move on to our
next question.
>> Uh, next question. What is the will of
God or what does he want us to do?
>> Good question, brother Dre. What is his
will and what is it he wants us to do?
>> Let's go to Deuteronomy the 10th
chapter. Deuteronomy 10.
And we going to read verses 12 and 13.
Deuteronomy 102 and 13. When you get
there, go ahead, Tanzel.
And now, Israel, what did the Lord thy
God require of thee? But to fear the
Lord thy God, to walk in all his ways,
and to love him, and to serve the Lord
thy God with all thy heart, and with all
thy soul.
>> He said, walk in all his ways. This is
what he requires of us. To love him, not
some of his ways.
To serve the Lord with all our heart and
with all our soul. Verse 13.
>> To keep the commandments of the Lord and
his statutes, which I command thee this
day for thy good.
>> For this is for our good, and this is
what the Lord requires of us. Let's go
to Ecclesiastes 12 and we'll read verses
13 and 14.
Go ahead when you get it, brother.
>> Let us hear the conclusion of the whole
matter. Fear God and keep his
commandments. For this is the whole duty
of man.
>> This ain't the part duty of man. It's
the whole duty of man. Go ahead. For God
shall bring every word to judgment with
every secret thing, whether it be good
or whether it be evil.
>> So this is what the Lord requires of us
and this is what he wants us to do. His
will, whatever he commanded us is what
we should do.
>> That's all I got.
>> Yeah. Brother Dre said, "If you love me,
keep my command."
>> Amen. Yes, sir. Thank you, brother, for
that like. Hope that answered their
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Uh, next one. Sister Tanisha asks, "What
does it mean in Leviticus 19 verse 19
when it says, neither shall a garment
mingle of linen and woolen come upon
thee?"
>> All right, a garment is mingled with
linen as well as wool in Leviticus 19
and 19. Let's go there and then open it
up to the panel.
Leviticus 19 and 19.
>> Go ahead, brother.
>> Ye shall keep my statutes. Thou shall
not let thy cattle ginger with the
diverse kind.
Thou and thou shalt not sow thy field
with mingle seed, neither shall a
garment mingle of linen and woolen come
upon thee.
>> All right, opening to the panel. What is
the don't mix the linen and the wool
together in that verse 19?
>> I mean, what it say you know?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Linen is
uh one type of fabric and wool is a is
another type of fabric. And those were
the two fabrics mentioned in that verse.
It say don't mingle those two fabrics
together.
>> Right. Right. Yep. Just like it did with
the with the cattle and the gender and
with the seed that you go plant. So
that's the rule he set down. And um
there's nothing else we can say about
that. Skip up to verse 19 and one. Tanz
read that one verse.
>> And the Lord spake it to Moses saying
>> that's it brother right there. So like
brother Jerome said hey it just said
don't mix them them two together there.
So, we'll have to leave that right there
as we uh continue to move right on along
to our next question.
>> Uh next question. Uh the the job related
as in the end times lessons Daniel 7
verse 24 is explained that the 10 horns
are the 10 kingdom nations of the
European Union. The EU currently has 27
countries. Is there going to be a split
in the EU?
>> All right. The first question was
dealing with Daniel 7 and 24. Tanzel,
let's go there. And then they want to
know about the split 27 countries etc.
And the guest caller will share some
light from there.
All right. Daniel 7 and 24.
And the 10 horns out of this kingdom are
10 kings that shall arise, and another
shall arise after them. And he shall be
diverse from the first, and he shall
subdue three kings.
All right, guest caller, you with us?
>> Okay. Can you hear me now?
>> Yes, sir.
Well,
Western U
got together and decided that they would
get these 10 nations to represent them
and to set the uh uh to set the agenda.
Nation is not going to split because
what's going to happen is these 10 is
going to call the direction of all of
Western Europe. See, it used to be just
or it used to be Western European Union.
Now they just call it the European
Union. So these guys are these nations,
these 10 nations are the ones that the
all of Western Europe decided that they
wanted to represent them.
That's all they got to say.
>> All right. Okay. We're going to leave it
right there. And uh Sad Deborah, are we
going into new territory?
>> Uh yes, we are. Uh we are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday, May the
13th, 2026.
And Grecia asks, "Does Romans 14:es
1-10
mean the d the dietary law is done away
with?" Absolutely
not. Dietary law is not done away with.
Um, but let's go to Romans 14.
What scripture, Deborah?
>> Uh, Romans 14:es
1-10.
>> Romans 14 1-10. Well, we're going to
open it up to the panel and um ask
brother Tanzel to begin to read that.
But um dietary law still stands. Go
ahead, brother.
>> Him that is weak in the faith receive
ye, but not to doubtful disputation. For
one belie that he may eat all things,
and another who is weak eat of herbs.
Let him that eate of despise him that
eate of not, and let not him which eate
of not judge him that eateth. For God
hath received him.
Who art thou that judgeth another man's
servant to his own mouth he standeth for
fall? Yeah, he shall be holding up for
God is able to make him stand. One man
esteem one day above another, another
esteemed every day alike, that every man
be fully persuaded in his own mind.
He that regardeth the day regardeth it
unto the Lord. And he that regardeth not
the day to the Lord. He doeth not
regarded. He that eateth eate to the
Lord. For he giveth God thanks. He that
eateth not to the Lord he eateth not and
giveth God thanks. But none of us liveth
to himself. And no man dieth to himself.
For whether we live, we live unto the
Lord. Whether we die, we die unto the
Lord. And whether we live, therefore, or
die, we are the Lord's.
>> Hold on. Can I Can I jump in?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Let's Let's go to second Thessalonians,
the first chapter.
Because he's talking about one eating
herbs and another one eating
one is a vegetarian, the other one is
eating meat. It's not talking about
unclean meats.
I want to show you about the coming of
the Lord and how he is going to judge
people. Let's go. That don't know God by
by the way. So, let's go to 2
Thessalonians the first chapter. Pick it
up at verse
seven.
I pick it up at six. Go ahead, brother.
And now you know what withholders that
he might be.
>> I'm sorry. Second Thessalonians the
first chapter. Second Thessalonians the
first chapter. Pick it up at verse 6.
>> See it is a righteous thing with God to
recompense tribulation to them that
trouble you
>> and to you who are troubled rest with
us. For the Lord Jesus shall be revealed
from heaven with his mighty angels. Now
the Lord is coming one time and he's
coming with his mighty angels. And what
is he going to do? Go ahead. In flaming
fire taking vengeance of them that know
not God and that obey not the gospel of
our Lord Jesus Christ.
>> So those that don't know God and those
that don't obey the gospel, he is going
to take vengeance on them. Go ahead. who
shall be punished with everlasting
destruction from the presence of the
Lord and from the glory of his power.
>> And that is the vengeance that he is
going to take. Now, let's go read about
this same thing that he is going to do
and what these people are eating at this
time. Let's go to Isaiah 66
and pick it up at verse 15. This is the
same time, same coming of the Lord.
Verse 15, go ahead.
>> For behold, the Lord will come with fire
and with his terror like a whirlwind.
>> Mhm.
>> Surrender his anger with fury and his
rebuke with flames of fire.
>> So the Lord is coming with anger and
rebuke with flames of fire. Go ahead.
For by fire and by his sword will the
Lord plead with all flesh, and the slain
of the Lord shall be many.
>> So nobody is telling you about this.
They telling you about the love of
Jesus. But the Lord is coming on with
judgment on them that obey not God. Go
ahead. And they that sanctified
themselves and purified themselves in
the garden behind one tree in the midst
eating swine flesh and the abomination
in the mouse shall be consumed together
sayeth the Lord.
>> This is what the Lord is saying. So the
Lord is telling you, they that sanctify
themselves and purify themselves in the
gardens behind one tree in the midst,
eating swine's flesh and the abomination
because it's an abomination
and the mouse shall be consumed
together. So don't let nobody twist you
up because Romans 14 is talking about
one eating meat and another one eating
vegetables. It don't in the beginning of
that you could read that. But the Lord
is going to come and he's going to judge
those that know not God and don't obey
him. So please don't get twisted up with
that. That's all I got.
>> Yep. And brother Dre, let's let's go to
Leviticus 11:2 and show who gave the
dietary law so we know it's not done
away with. Leviticus 11.
>> Yes, sir.
And when you get there, Brother Tanzel,
we're going to do some skipping around,
but we encourage them to read this whole
chapter here. And then it's in um it's
also in Leviticus 14
that bags up Leviticus 11. So, we ask
that you read that, too. But let's read
that in Leviticus 11:1 and2 Chenzel. Let
then go do some skipping. Go ahead,
brother.
>> The Lord spake unto Moses and Aaron,
saying unto them, speaking to the
children of Israel, saying, "These are
the beasts which ye shall eat among all
the beasts that are on the earth."
>> So this is Moses
and Aaron listening to what the Lord
said about his dietary law. He gives you
the details about it there. Skip down to
verse nine and read. These shall ye eat
of all that are in the waters.
Whatsoever have fins and scales in the
waters, in the seas, and in the rivers,
them shall you eat.
>> So it got to have fins and scales, they
eliminate catfish, shrimp, lobster,
oysters, snails. Go ahead, brother. And
all that have not fans and scales in the
sea, and in the rivers, and all that
move in the waters, and of any living
thing which is in the waters, they shall
be an abomination unto you.
>> An abomination unto you. Go ahead.
>> They shall be even abomination unto you.
Ye shall not eat of their flesh, but ye
shall have their carcasses in
abomination.
>> Yep. 12.
So whatsoever have no fins, no scales in
the waters, that shall be an abomination
unto you.
>> And that's good for us today and even
beyond. Skip down, brother, and pick it
up at that verse
um 44.
Go ahead.
>> I am the Lord your God. Ye shall
therefore sanctify yourselves,
and ye shall be holy, for I am holy.
Neither shall ye defile yourself with
any man of creeping thing that creepeth
upon the earth.
>> Still the Lord speaking. Go ahead.
>> For I am the Lord that bringeth you up
out of the land of Egypt to be your God.
You shall therefore be holy. For I am
holy.
This is the law of the beast and of the
foul and of every living creature that
moveth in the waters and of every
creature that creepeth upon the earth.
that cover all the beasts. That covers
everything that the Lord just spoke
about, whether it's on land, sea, or in
the air. Go ahead.
>> To make a difference between the unclean
and the clean, and between the beast
that may be eaten and the beast that may
not be eaten.
>> That's all I get.
>> Good stuff, brother.
>> And it's Deuteronomy. Uh, it's
Deuteronomy the 14th chapter.
>> Yep. It will back that up also. So hey,
the dietary law is still good today,
tomorrow, and beyond us. So hey, thank
God for his dietary law. All right,
sister.
>> Daniel kept it. Daniel kept it and Peter
kept it.
>> Let let me throw something in.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Peter let you know that when they was
with Jesus that they was not dealing
with favorable, but he said, "We have a
surewood of prophecy." Will somebody go
read that?
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right. We're in search mode for
that.
[clears throat]
>> I think it's in second Peter the first
chapter.
>> Yeah, it is.
>> All right.
>> 19.
>> You if you want to
>> verse 16.
>> Yeah, you can go to 16. Yeah.
>> Second Peter.
>> Second Peter 1 and 16. Tanville.
>> For we have not followed cunning divas
fables when we made known unto you the
power and coming of our Lord Jesus
Christ, but were eyewitness of his
majesty.
>> Go ahead.
>> For he received from God the Father
honor and glory. where there came such a
voice to him from the excellency,
glory, this is my beloved son in whom I
am well pleased. And this voice which
came from heaven, we heard when we were
with him in the holy mount. We have also
a more sure word of prophecy. Where
until ye do well that ye take heed as
unto a light that shine up in a dark
place until the day dawn and the day
star arise in your hearts. Knowing this
first.
>> Finish that.
>> Go ahead.
>> Finish it.
>> Oh 20. knowing this verse that no
prophecy of the scripture of any private
interpretation.
For the prophecy came not in old time by
the will of man, but holy men of God
spake as they were moved by the Holy
Ghost.
>> So now Peter telling you,
>> even though we walked around with
Christ, now Peter was walking with
Christ. You understand?
>> Paul never was with walk with Christ
while he was on earth. And Peter man
that God said he left the Jesus said he
left the kings of the kingdom which said
we have a most sure word of prophecy.
Why did he say that? But somebody find
right quick where he says surely where
the Lord said he will do nothing but
reveal his secrets to his prophet.
Somebody find that and read it. Yeah.
Amos.
>> All right.
>> Search mode.
>> Amos 3 directly. Verse 7.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> You said Amos 3.
>> Yes sir.
>> And seven.
>> Amos 3 and verse seven. Surely the L
surely the Lord God will do nothing but
reveal his secrets unto his servants,
the prophets.
>> Now that's a big statement, isn't it?
>> Yep.
>> The Lord will do nothing
but receal his secrets to his prophet.
In other words, if it is not written in
the prophecy,
then
it is not written in the new book.
And ain't nowhere in the prophecy where
the Lord said you can eat anything.
>> Right.
>> But he so but so uh that's why Peter say
you have a more sure word of prophecy.
So if you confused about something,
somebody trying to tell you something,
you said let's go back and see what it
says in prophecy cuz the Lord said
surely he would do nothing but reveal
his secrets to his prophet. In other
words, he ain't going to make a move
without telling his prophets about it.
Right.
>> That's all I have to say. Yes, sir.
>> You're right. Guess Colin, you mentioned
Peter and like Peter said, he never ate
anything common or unclean
>> in his life.
>> All right. We hope that that answered
your question there, Sister Deborah. We
having fun and time is ticking. Where we
at?
>> All right. Uh, next question is from
Shanquilla Au. Joby asks, "If you leave
your food in the car on the Sabbath
while going to Sabbath class or for the
ones who have to work on that day and
the heat from the car warms it, is that
the same as food in the microwave?"
>> No, it's not.
>> No.
Nope.
>> Microwave is plugged in.
>> Yep. So, yeah, it's called a microwave
oven.
And also,
>> yeah, that's um people leave their food
in the car sometime to kind of warm it
up a little bit. So, you're not in
violation.
And we'll um continue to move on to our
next question with a time check.
>> Yes. The time is 8:43.
Uh, brother Otis stated someone said
Hebrews 13:E4
said it's okay to lay with your husband
or wife on the Sabbath. And they said it
doesn't say anything is wrong with doing
it on the Sabbath. I did use Leviticus
15 verse 18.
True.
>> All right. Leviticus 15 and 18,
>> right? That's what
>> the person said they use.
>> Laying with your spouse on the Sabbath
day is a violation of God's law, first
of all.
>> And
you know that's a part of doing your own
pleasure, which we can read that too.
But let's go and read that Leviticus, I
mean that Hebrews 13, I'm sorry,
brother. In verse four, where they going
to talk about, you know, marriage is
honorable and defile in the bed. Go
ahead, brother. Hebrews 13 and 4. And
let's open that up to the panel. Go
ahead. Marriage is honorable in all and
the bed undefiled,
but whoreongers and adulterers God will
judge.
Let me say right here, let let me
intervene that right there tell you
talking about
you understand it say let you know that
you're a whoreonger or you're a
fornicator God's going to judge you but
if you are married then you can come
together and it is honorable
that's all it's saying it if you read it
tells you what it is said read again
brother real careful and
Marriage is honorable in all in the bed
undefiled.
The whoreongers and adulterers
God will judge.
>> So those are the ones that defile the
bed. You whoreonger,
are you adulterer?
Are you a fornicator?
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's against law, God's law. It got
nothing to do dealing with on the
Sabbath day. You talking about uh uh and
the books that do uh uh uh uh don't do
your pleasures on the Sabbath day,
>> right?
>> So you telling your wife when you lay
with it, it ain't no pleasure.
[laughter]
>> I got
Let's go. Uh uh uh Exodus the 20th
chapter,
Kenzel. Exodus 20,
>> pick it up at verse 8. We just read a
couple of verses.
>> Remember the Sabbath day to keep it
open. Sixth day shall thou lay do all
thy work.
>> Yeah.
>> But the seventh day is the Sabbath of
the Lord thy God. In it thou shall not
do any work. thou, nor thy son, nor thy
daughter, thy man's servant, nor thy
maid servant, nor thy cattle, and nor
that stranger that is within thy gates.
For six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in the
midst, and rested the seventh day. And
wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hallowed it.
>> So he gave you six days to do all your
labor, your labor, and your pleasure.
And so he said, "Take take a break one
day. Just one day.
>> Don't pollute the Lord. Sabbath day."
>> Hey, can we can we read Isaiah 58 and13?
>> Yeah. Hey uh Dre, let's go there. Let's
read that um Leviticus that the brother
say he used to try and correct that.
Then read yours cuz
>> Okay.
>> The one he used is not talking about the
Sabbath day either. That Leviticus 15
and verse 18. 18. Yes.
>> Okay. Okay. And let's see if we see the
Sabbath day even in this one. Leviticus
15 and 18.
Leviticus 15 and 18.
>> Yep.
>> The woman also with whom man shall lie
with seed of population. They shall both
bathe themselves in water and be unclean
until the evening.
So that's not dealing with the s Sabbath
day there,
>> right?
>> Just telling you any days other than the
Sabbath. Now, Brother Dre, because he
said he used that, but you have one
that'll really hit the nail on the head.
What' you say, brother?
>> Isaiah 58 verse 13. And I got one other
place after that.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Isaiah 50. Because you might say this
ain't no pleasure
what you doing. But let's let's look at
it. Go ahead.
>> If thou turn away thy foot from the
Sabbath, from doing thy pleasure on my
holy day, and call the Sabbath a
delight, the holy of the Lord honorable,
and shall honor him not doing thy own
ways, nor finding thy own pleasure, nor
speaking thy own words.
>> Go ahead.
Then shalt thou delight thyself in the
Lord, and I will cause thee to ride upon
the high places of the earth, and feed
thee with the heritage of Jacob thy
father, for the mouth of the Lord have
spoken ite.
>> So being with your wife is a pleasure.
How do we know that? Let's go to Genesis
18 and read verse 12.
>> There you go. There you go, Dre.
Promised her a son.
>> There you go.
Genesis 18 and 12. Read that when you
get it, brother.
>> Therefore Sarah lie within herself,
saying after I am wax old, shall I have
pleasure, my lord being also.
>> So Sarah talked about having pleasure
cuz she going to have a baby,
>> right?
>> How did she get the baby? She had some
pleasure.
>> [laughter]
>> That's right, Dre. And she she was old.
She was what, 90 years old at that time.
>> Yes, sir.
>> When she made that statement. So, hey,
brother. Yes, them was two good points
to go and shed some some light on. For
sure. So, um, no, brother, you're not
supposed to be laying with your wife on
the Sabbath day,
>> right? Lord, the Lord said anyway,
remember the Sabbath day and keep it
holy. What's holy about having sex?
H.
>> Nope. Nope. So, hey.
>> Yep. So, that's a no. No. Yeah, we seen
that on the internet. Somebody put that
out there talking about it's okay to do
that. We telling you that it is not
okay. That is wrong information put out.
So, all right, sister Deborah, we going
to our next question.
>> Next one. Grecia asks, "What is an
abomination?
And will you go to the lake of fire for
not keeping the dietary law?"
>> I think an abomination covered that a
little bit.
>> Yeah. Dre, didn't you didn't you cover
that?
>> We just We just read Isaiah 66.
>> That's right.
He said and he said you going to be
consumed together with all them sinners
and everybody else when the Lord come.
>> Read it again to him Dre.
>> Let's go back there.
>> Yeah.
>> Verse 15. Pick it up.
>> Is it there?
>> Yes sir.
>> Isa Isaiah 66 and verse 15.
>> No, just read 17 cuz we read it already.
But read 174.
They that sanctify,
>> go ahead.
>> They that sanctify themselves and purify
themselves in the gods behind one tree
in the midst, eating swine flesh. And
the abomination and the mouse shall be
consumed together, sayeth the Lord.
>> So they they going to be consumed. What
do you think that is?
They ain't in the kingdom
of fire.
Let me read this.
>> Go ahead, guess
>> that one tree in the midst of the garden
is Satan, the devil.
Tell
>> gohead on you can eat some pig. The Lord
ain't going to put you in the lake of
fire for that. Well, then he told Eve uh
to eat of the tree of knowledge good and
evil. You will not die. God know that
you be as God knowing good and evil.
>> We dying a
>> day. And this is at the coming of the
Lord. This is when the Lord come.
>> He going to deal with you like this.
>> That's right.
>> Yeah.
>> Let me read uh let me read this uh
definition on abomination.
>> Yeah.
>> Said an abomination is something that
causes extreme disgust.
>> Yep.
>> Loathing. It is a thing or action that
is considered vile, shameful,
detestable.
and and and brother Cornell read
Leviticus 11 and showed you that these
things are an abomination and how you
make a difference between the unclean
and the clean and the things that should
be eaten and the things that should not
be eaten.
>> That's right. Yep. Yep. So please don't
let your
dietary lawn and stuff you eat get you
in trouble with the Lord. Who does he
say and save yourself from this unto
generation? All right, sister Deborah.
Our next question.
>> Next one. Serena Kendall asks, "What is
the right thing to do according to God's
word when one person of the remnant in
my state attends holy convocations
but lives in a home where ashes are kept
in and earned."
>> All right. Sounds like that's out of
they control. But let's Julius, go
ahead.
asses make you unclean.
>> Yep. So, um they saying that they they
stay in a home where somebody keep it
keep their ashes there. And um guess
caller, you got anything else for that?
>> Yeah. Move.
>> Yep. My
>> All right.
>> Way to deal with
>> scripture cannot be broken. All right.
Let's move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Be alert ask, could you please
provide me some scriptures that defines
wickedness in God's eyes, especially
when it's Christmas and Easter.
>> All right, let's open that up to the
panel. Uh script scripture or two about
dealing with wickedness. And they asked
for
uh what was the days they asked for
sister?
>> Uh especially
when it's Christmas and Easter.
>> All right, let's go to Christmas first
then. Let's go Jeremiah 10th chapter.
>> And when you get there, Tanzo, go ahead
pick it up at that verse one.
Jeremiah 10
and verse
one.
Hear ye the word which the Lord speaketh
unto you, oh house of Israel.
>> Thus sayeth the Lord. Learn not the way
of the heathen, and be not dismayed at
the signs of heaven. For the heathens
are dismayed at them, for the custom of
the people are vain.
For one cutth a tree out of the forest,
the work of the hands of the workmen
with the axe
with silver.
>> Go ahead.
>> They deck it with silver and with gold.
They fasten with nails and with hammers
that it move not. They are upright as
the palm tree, but speak not. They must
knees be born because they cannot go. Be
not afraid of them, for they cannot do
evil, neither also is it in them to do
good.
>> So we talking about the tree here
dealing with the season of Christmas.
How they go and decorate it and cut it
down, kill the tree, and then say it
represent life. But skip down and read
that verse eight, brother, and that'd be
all I got.
>> They are all together brutous and
foolish. The stock is a doctrine of
vanities.
>> It's foolish to do that because it don't
mean nothing. Anybody else?
All right. Now, that other Does anybody
have anything dealing with uh Easter?
>> Well, they said they observe Easter
because Christ died on Good Friday and
rose Easter Sunday morning.
>> They can't read. That is not in the
Bible. That is pagan.
>> Yeah. In fact, Easter uh uh is when they
celebrate uh goddess of fertilities
where they have sacred uh uh temple
prostitutes.
>> Yep.
>> Now, you said Jesus rose on Easter
Sunday morning. If you go, what is it?
Was it Matthew's 12 where he said Jesus
said he going to be in the grave for
three days and three nights, right?
>> Matthew 12 38-4,
>> right? Somebody go read that.
Somebody
>> search mode.
>> Matthew 12:38-4.
>> Matthew 12 38-
40.
>> Wait, bro.
There certain of the scribes and other
Pharisees answered, saying, "Master,
we would see a sign from thee." But he
answered and said unto them, an evil and
adulterous generation seeketh after a
sign. For there should no sign be given
to it, but the sign of the prophet
Jonas. For as Jonas was three days and
three nights in the whale's belly, so
shall the Son of Man be three days and
three nights in the heart of the earth.
Now I want you to get f count from
Friday evening to to Easter Sunday
morning and see if you can get three
days and three nights.
>> Right?
>> You can't do it. So if he died good
Friday and rose Easter Sunday morning,
then he and then he is not the that is
not the Jesus. He's not the Christ,
>> right?
>> Jesus didn't die on Friday and neither
did he rise Sunday. Easter is pagan. Why
don't you go on your encyclopedia and
look under Easter and it'll tell you
where it came from. That's all I got to
say.
>> Yeah. I think it's even a lesson on that
guest caller. Eastern a pagan festival
not holy.
>> That is right. Order that lesson that'll
educate.
>> Yeah. Al also for other part of your
question you can read Galatians 5:16
on through there and it it'll it'll help
you with that to recognize wickedness.
>> Yeah. Okay. All right, Sister Deborah,
let us go with our last question of the
evening.
>> All right. And it's dealing with uh
ashes again. Raja Armstrong says, "My
wife has her brother and dead ashes
inside the house. I had a talk with her
about it being unclean, but she is
having a hard time taking them out of
the house. Any advice?" and Genesis he
gives Genesis 3 verse 19 and
Ecclesiastes
12 verse 7.
>> All right.
>> Genesis 39.
>> Yeah. So he wants to know is there any
advice you can give them?
>> All right.
>> Yeah. Yeah. You're the head of the
household. Throw them out.
Your house is unclean. Makes you
unclean.
>> That's right. You the man, the head of
the household.
>> Yep. And then and your the house is
continually unclean. I mean, day after
day after day.
>> And you are too.
>> Yep. And you are too. Maybe you could
maybe you can convince her to take go
somewhere and you all bury it somewhere.
Bury the ashes somewhere else, you know,
instead of in the house.
>> Yeah.
>> Not in the backyard neither,
>> right? And Yeah. Yeah. That's it. Not in
the backyard. That Genesis 3:19 where
you gave her where it say for dust thou
art and unto dust shall thou return.
That is true. Let her know that's in a
violation too. The Lord expect for us to
return the dead back to the ground from
whence they came.
So wish you the best with that
situation. And um
>> Ecclesiastes, right? And Ecclesiastes 12
verse 7.
>> Go there quickly. Chandel Ecclesiastes
12 and 7.
>> Yeah, another good one there. Go ahead,
read it, brother.
>> Then shall the dust return to the earth
as it was, and the spirit shall return
unto God who gave it.
>> Yep. So
maybe she'll um open her eyes to receive
that because that does tie right into
that Genesis that you read to her also.
But that's all we got on that. And um we
like to say, Sister Deborah, we have ran
out of time. Correct.
>> Yes. It's 9:02.
>> All right. And we like to say to
everybody that if you submitted a
question, we didn't have a chance to get
to it. Please don't resubmit it. Sister
Deborah would take it. put it in
rotation and we will address that
question next Wednesday on our Q&A
session. So until we all come together
again, we want to thank you all for
viewing and we say be safe out there, be
blessed, stay prayed up and may the Lord
have mercy on us all as brother Tanzel
closes us out.
>> Our Father which are in heaven, hallowed
be thy name, thy kingdom come, thy will
be done in earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread. And
forgive us of our debts as we forgive
our debtors. And lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom and the power
and the glory forever.